Morten Vester Pedersen

DATA SCIENTIST · STRATEGY CONSULTANT

mortenvester1 | mortenvesterpedersen

Summary .

Currently leading a team of +25 practioners focused on delivering data-driven and analytics applications in the Azure cloud. I design and implement machine learning pipelines, RESTful APIs, ETL and CI/CD pipelines. With +3 years of experience in data science, I have developed interests in MLOps, DevOps, software development, machine learning frameworks, and solution architecture.

Technical Skills_

Programming Python, Scala, Swift, Node.js, SQL, R, Matab

Machine Learning Spark, Azure Machine Learning, Pandas, XGBoost, Scikit-Learn, PyTorch

Cloud & Others Azure, AWS, Ansible, REST API, Docker, Kubernetes, git, D3.js

Work Experience

Managing Data Scientist & Strategy Consultant

IBM Services

- I help clients explore datasources, design and implement data ingestion pipelines, and develop machine learning solutions for deployment in their cloud environment.
- Advise clients on machine learning techniques, open source solutions, MLOps, and help outline development and deployment plans.
- Develop solution architectures to deliver an end-to-end experience from data ingestion to user consumption.
- As a manager I mentor and coach junior developers and data scientist, to develop their technical skillset through one-on-one and technical sessions.

Data Scientist - Machine Learning Engineer

IBM ANALYTICS

- Work with external clients on formulating data science projects solving business problems in various industries, through data-discovery and brainstorming sessions.
- Through a period of up to 90 days, I help deliver a minimal viable product, encompassing a full pipeline from data ingestion and wrangling to a deployed model.

Data Scientist

AOL INC.

- Helped build a slack-integrated natural language based bot for obtaining insights and metrics from digital advertisment data.
- Responsible for backend software development in Python focusing on data analytics, visualization and presentation using AWS, Spark and D3.js.

New York, United States Jan 2018 - Feb 2019

New York, United States

Feb 2019 - Current

New York, United States

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017

Education

Master of Science in Scientific Computing

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY - COURANT INSTITATE OF MATHEMATICAL SCIENCES

Bachelor of Science in Science and IT

University of Copenhagen - Department of Computer Science

New York, United States Sep 2015 - May 2017

Copenhagen, Denmark

Sep 2012 - Jun 2015

Publications _

Finding Significantly Connected Voxels Based on Histograms of Connection Strenghts

PEDERSEN, M., KASENBURG, N., DARKNER, S.

• Implemented a large scale hypothesis testing algorithm, analyzed tractography results of 40 subjects and constructed connectivity based segmentations of the human thalamus.

SPIE Medical Imaging

2016